Welcome back guys, to another module,
to the advanced direct Response Editor training.
In this module, we're gonna go over part three, the pre WEX to video editing.
Okay, I'm not gonna do the whole thing in that voice.
I think that would be really exhausting. So let's get into it guys.
Alright. First off, what do you need to get started?
You're gonna need a PC and a Mac. That should be relatively high performance,
okay? If you're working off a potato, I don't recommend taking this course.
You should probably go to Best Buy and order something. Um, no, but in real,
real talk, if you're an editor,
your gear is incredibly important and you know that if you have crappy gear,
you're not gonna be able to perform as well.
You're gonna lag if your graphics card isn't up to speed.
If you don't have enough ram,
all of these things are gonna affect your productivity and you want to ensure
you have the best of the best if you can't afford it.
And if you can't afford it,
you'll work up to a point where you can't afford it and that's how you get nice
stuff. So I always recommend maxing out on ram,
whatever your motherboard can support, whether that's 32 gigs,
64 1 28, I, I think I have 32,
but I'm, you know, I'm very RAM focused. I love having a million tabs open,
uh, tons of programs open at one time. Uh,
next thing is getting an external s s d.
If you don't already have an SS s d built into your PC or Mac,
get an external one on Amazon. These things like get a,
get a terabyte or more,
they run so much faster than a typical hard drive. Uh,
so that's just one thing.
It is just like a must just get an Ss s d if you can, if you have the space,
if you have the resources, get dual monitors.
I always prefer that you can have two screens where you can toggle in between
your notes while editing. You don't have to keep minimizing.
I feel like having two screens has made me so much faster,
but it's also created a lot of distraction as well.
'cause you have more things to look at.
But I really like it because on one screen I can look at stock footage,
I can look at the script, I can, you know,
scrub footage or I can move my timeline into the other screen and
focus on this area. So, you know,
just having more real estate visually is always a good thing.
I used to have four monitors at one point and it just got too excessive where I
just had too much stuff going on and then it would slow me down and don't
recommend doing that. So I think two is optimal. Next,
high performance graphics card. This is obviously,
it's a no brainer if you're working with graphics in any capacity or if you're a
gamer, you're gonna need a fast performance, high performance graphics card.
So get what you can afford.
I'm not here to break down the exact specifics.
I'm so out of touch with what's out there in terms of what's really good.
I used to build my own PCs when I was a kid,
but now I've just switched to Mac and I just try to, I don't get the Max,
max Mac. That sounds weird. The Max Mac,
because that s**t comes out to like 15 grand.
I'm not gonna throw 15 grand on a computer when if you build a BC you can get
double the performance for like a fraction of the cost. Alright? Number two,
you're gonna need a legit version of Adobe Premier Pro.
If you use another program,
just absorb the principles and apply them to your software.
'cause really what we're learning here are the foundations, are the principles,
are the techniques. Uh, if you're using Final Cut, if you're using Da Vinci,
if you're using, what are the other ones? Uh, apple, you know,
iMovie, whatever the case may be. What you need to understand is, you know,
it's all the same. Doesn't matter what program you're using. It, it,
the concepts are really what's important.
'cause you can translate the concept in any editing program that you're using.
For example, your phone, like I use my phone,
I use cap cut to edit a lot of videos for social media.
There's pros and cons to everything.
No program is perfect and whatever you're used to using,
I highly suggest using that. But this program,
this training course will be predominantly Premier Pro. Okay,
next, you're gonna need time, focus, and patience. Okay? That's very important.
Things take time to learn. Okay? When you're learning something new,
you have to be very focused and present because you're taking in new
information. It's almost like riding a bike. Again,
maybe some of this stuff is brand new to you,
so your brain is gonna kind of be stretching itself,
which is always a good thing. And don't get frustrated and, you know,
just be patient with the process because learning takes time.
And you will over time with practice become very proficient.
You'll be able to talk about this stuff and you'll be able to identify patterns
and things that, you know, will be second nature to you.
It's just like learning an instrument over, over months, over years,
you become very fluid and you'll be able to freestyle.
You'll be able to do whatever you want.
And I've always wanted to be a really good piano player,
but I just never put in the time focus and patience. So that's my fault.
Okay. Number four, have a beginner's mindset.
I know everybody comes from different backgrounds and, and,
and different experiences and different skill sets.
So try to learn all this stuff with a blank slate or continue to,
you know,
adopt that open-mindedness because when you come in here with a lot of your,
your, your beliefs and whatnot, it can get in the way of your progress.
And I've worked with a lot of people in the past who've kind of come from a
different production world or they did a lot of TV and this person did a lot of
movies and so we clashed a lot in terms of principles and whatnot. But,
you know, at the end of the day,
what I'm just trying to teach you are additional tools to add to your belt.
So you can take what you know here and take what you know there and cross apply
them and then come up with something completely unique.
And I think that's the beauty of continually acquiring more information is then
you'll have a broader perspective of life. Alright,
so this is my setup right now. I've got the Max Studio 2022.
We've got 64 Giga gram. Oh yeah, yeah, that's pretty, pretty good. Um,
I got one terabyte SS s d two wide widescreen monitors. They're,
they're huge. Uh, I've had 'em for years and I'm rolling with the MX Master
Master three Logitech Mouse. I love this thing. Um,
primarily for the grip right here. If you do a lot of editing,
you're gonna run into a lot of like, wrists problems right here. I,
I think for one, at one point in my life I had basic minor carpal tunnel,
and it was because my mouse was too small.
I was using like this little gaming mouse, like it was tiny like this.
And I was making this movement.
And then all of my joints right here started to just be in pain all the time.
And, um, if I'm not working out, if I'm not lifting,
if I'm not doing any weights or anything like that, it starts to flare up again.
And this mouse is wide enough, uh,
where it kind of gives me enough support and my fingers are able to stretch wide
enough. 'cause it's not giving me that like, like crabby crab fingers,
which I feel like is, uh, is the reason why I, I was getting like carpal tunnel,
but it's a really common thing. So definitely invest in the right stuff. Uh,
you're gonna be,
you're sitting behind a computer a lot and you wanna be comfortable,
like get a nice chair, you know, invest in,
in your stuff because this is your job.
This is where you're putting a lot of your time and energy and you wanna make
sure you've got the best gear, you and, and the most comfort. And,
and primarily, primarily obviously protecting your health. 'cause um, you know,
we,
us editors can sit here for hours and just like be pieces of s**t for a while.